Guide to the Maurice Hindus papers M2002
Special Collections and University Archives, Colgate University Libraries
Maurice Hindus papers
1910-1971
M2002
Special Collections and University Archives, Colgate University Libraries
10 Cubic feet
Hindus, Maurice Gerschon, 1891-1969
Access to Collection
Collection is open for research.
Materials Cataloged Separately
The Maurice Hindus papers include a number of published volumes. The following volumes have been removed and are cataloged:
The Black Book: The Nazi Crime against the Jewish People. New York, NY: The Jewish Black Book Committee, 1946.
Hindus, Maurice Gerschon.The Great Offensive. New York: H. Smith and R. Haas, 1933.
Hindus, Maurice Gerschon.Green Worlds: An Informal Chronicle. Garden City, NY: Book League of America, 1938.
Hindus, Maurice Gerschon.Humanity Uprooted. New York: J. Cape & H. Smith, 1929. (2 copies)
Hindus, Maurice Gerschon.In Search of a Future; Persia, Egypt, Iraq and Palestine. Garden City, NY: Doubleday, 1949.
Hindus, Maurice Gerschon.Red Bread. New York: J. Cape & H. Smith, 1931.
Samuel, Maurice.The Worlds of Maurice Samuel: Selected Writings. Philadelphia: Jewish Publication Society of America, 1977.
Soviet Union--History--1925-1953.; Soviet Union--Politics and government.
- Personal correspondence, 1924-1969
  - TLS from Louis Adamic, New York City, to Maurice Hindus regarding Common Ground, 1940 May 23; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - TLS from Louis J. Alber, Cleveland, Ohio, to Maurice Hindus regarding agents meeting, 1925 November 23; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - TLS from Louis J. Alber, Cleveland, Ohio, to Maurice Hindus regarding contract, 1927 November 29; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - ALS from Alice, North Brookfield, New York, to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1963 September 29; 2 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - TL from American Consulate General, Praha, to Maurice Hindus regarding immediate departure, 1938 September 23; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - ALS from David Astor, Kent, to Maurice Hindus, undated; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - TL from Maurice Hindus to Lady Astor, undated; 3 pages (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - ALS from Lady Astor to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1938 June 19; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - ALS from Carl Baum, Hamilton, New York, to Maurice Hindus regarding borrowed book, 1958 January 10; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - TLS from Joseph Barnes, New York, New York, to Maurice Hindus regarding Harriet Moore, 1941 September 26; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - ALS from Carl W. Baum, Hamilton, New York to Maurice Hindus regarding news, 1931 June 23; 3 pages (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - ALS from Carl W. Baum, Hamilton, New York to Maurice Hindus regarding latest book and Hamilton news, 1939 May 28; 3 pages (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - TLS from Theodore Bayer, New York City, to Maurice Hindus regarding meeting, 1939 May 11; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - TL, TC from Maurice Hindus to Waldorf Hotel, Aldwych, & W.C.2, Arnold Bennett, John Galsworthy, Lord Beaverbook, H.G. Wells, George Bernard Shaw, and Herman Ould Esq. regarding Katayev, 1930 December 2; 5 pages (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - TLS from Marshall A. Best, New York, New York to Maurice Hindus regarding Shostakovitch and Steinbeck, 1950 August 29; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - TLS from Marshall A. Best, New York, New York, to Maurice Hindus regarding Russian Purge and the Extraction of Confession, 1951 January 25; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - TLS from Bill [William Parker] to Maurice Hindus regarding personal and thank you, 1968 November 10; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Maurice Hindus, New York City, to Editor of the Boston Post, 1938 March 24; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Scope and Contents note
    See copy of "Murder Justified."
  - TLS from Bill to Maurice Hindus regarding jacket, 1968 November 23; 2 pages (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - TLS from Bruce Bliven, New York, New York to Maurice Hindus regarding "Russia Today", 1941 October 8; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - TLS from Everett Case, Colgate University, to Maurice Hindus regarding foreign policy conference, 1950 April 6; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - ALS from Bernard C. Clausen, Ohio, to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1955 October 5; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - TLS from Mr. and Mrs. Barry A. Corten, California, to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1968 June 6; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - TL from Hindus, Jamestown, Tennessee, to Carl C. Dickey regarding interview with Stalin, 1928 April 27; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - ALS from Dotty [Dorothy Kling Hadfield], Oriskany Falls, New York, to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1964 February 7; 3 pages (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - E. Christiansen, Nelson, B.C. to Maurice Hindus regarding Doukhobors, 1969 April 2; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - TL from Maurice Hindus to the editor of the Colgate Maroon regarding Black Cultural Center, 1968-1969; 5 pages (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - TL from Dotty [Dorothy Kling Hadfield], Oriskany Falls, New York, to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1965 September 9; 2 pages (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - TLS from V.E., Prague, to Maurice Hindus regarding freedom, 1939 June 28; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - TLS from Ed, Moscow, to Maurice Hindus, no year October 12; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - TLS from Ed Deuss, Moscow, to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1929 March 20; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - TLS from Maurice Hindus, London, to Ed Deuss regarding personal, 1929 October 27; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Ed Deuss, London, to Maurice Hindus regarding Dr. Peters, 1940 February 16; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - TL from Maurice Hindus, New York, New York to Justice William O. Douglas regarding personal, 1952 January 27; 2 pages (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - ALS from L.D. Edie, University of Chicago, to Maurice Hindus regarding checks, 1928 March 23; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - TLS from Ernestine Evans, Wedderburn, Vienna, Virginia, to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1940; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - TLS from F.E. Frank, Barnhart, Missouri, to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1969 February 16; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - TLS from Joseph Freedman, New York, to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1928 January 21; 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - TLS from Joseph Freeman to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1941 August 24; 3 pages (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - TL from Maurice Hindus to Mr. Fierlinger regarding personal, 1948; 3 pages (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - ALS from Frida to Maurice Hindus regarding relatives in San Francisco, visit, 1936 April 8; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - TL from editor of the Frederick News, New York, New York to Maurice Hindus regarding James Flood, 1947 April 1; 3 pages (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - TLS from Joseph Freeman to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1939 May 19; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - TLS from Joseph Freeman to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1939 May 24; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - TLS from Joseph Freeman, New York City, 1940 August 3; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - TL from Joseph Freeman, New York City, to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1940 December 2; 5 pages (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - TLS from Joseph Freeman, New York City, to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1941 August 22; 4 pages (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - TLS from Joseph Freeman, New York City, to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1941 December 27; 2 pages (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - TL from Maurice Hindus to Donald Friede, 1958 April 29; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - TL from Hindus, Shanghai, to Mr. Froelick regarding "booriats", 1927 September 15; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - TLS from J.D. Froelick, New York, New York, to Maurice Hindus regarding Harrison Smith, 1928 April 28; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Marion Galbraith to Walter Ricks, Ellison White Celebrity Bureau to Marian Galbraith, California; Oregon, regarding attitude towards communism, 1925 November 5; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - TLS from W. Horsley Gantt, Baltimore, to Maurice Hindus regarding guest book, 1967 January 6; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - ALS from Elwood Gates to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1967 March 12; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - TLS from John Haynes Holmes, New York City to Maurice Hindus and TL from Maurice Hindus, New York, New York to John Haynes Holmes regarding purges, 1938 January 25 and 1938 January 27; 3 pages (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - TLS from John Haynes Holmes, New York City to Maurice Hindus regarding reply to letter of Jan. 27th, 1938 January 28; 2 pages (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - TLS from Milton Hindus, Massachusetts, to Maurice Hindus regarding The Old East Side, 1967 April 14; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - ALS-German from Helen, Prague, to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1938 December 11; 2 pages (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - TLS from Helen, Praha to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1946 June 7; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - TLS from Helen, Praha to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1950 October 27; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - TLS from Helen, Praha, to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1964 April 22; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - TLS from Helen, Praha, to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1965 March 3; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - TLS from Helen, Praha, to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1966 December 5; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - TLS from Helen to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1968 April 6; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - TLS from Helen, Praha to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1968 May 5; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - TLS from Helen, Praha, to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1968 September 15; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - TLS from Helen, Praha, to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1968 December 3; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - TLS from Helen, Praha, to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1969 March 18; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - TLS from Julius Hendel, Minneapolis, to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1968 August 23; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - TLS from Julius Hendel to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1949 July 14; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - TL from Anonymous, Czechoslovakia to Maurice Hindus regarding Crimes against the people, 1939 November 20; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - TL from Maurice Hindus, New York to Mr. Armstrong and TLS from Hamilton Fish Armstrong, New York, New York to Maurice Hindus regarding Novy Mir clipping, 1951 August 12 and 1951 July 31; 2 pages (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - TL from Maurice Hindus to Joseph Barnes, 1950s [Wednesday evening]; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - TL from Maurice Hindus, New York to Huebsh regarding Shostakovich & Steinbeck, 1950 August 25; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - TL from Maurice Hindus to Horsley Gantt regarding manuscript, 1952 June 28; 2 pages (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - TLS from Horsley Gantt, Perry Point, Maryland, to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1968 February 13; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - TLS from Horsley Gantt, Perry Point, Maryland to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1969 May 7; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - TL from Maurice Hindus to George regarding personal, 1963 April 12; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - TLS from Herman J. Getzoff, New York, New York to Maurice Hindus regarding use of article, 1949 August 15; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - TLS-German from Frank Goldschmied, Prague, to Maurice Hindus, 1938 January 3; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - TLS-German from Frank Goldschmied, Prague to Maurice Hindus, 1938 November 26; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - TLS from R. Dean Goodwin, Pennsylvania to Maurice Hindus regarding religion in USSR, 1965 February 25; 2 pages (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - TLS from Charles O. Gorham, New York, New York to Maurice Hindus regarding letter, verses, lunch, 1941 October 30; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - TL from Maurice Hindus to Dr. Anna Gosline regarding explains his interest in mental illness, 1956 June 22; 2 pages (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - ALS from Baltimore, Maryland to Maurice Hindus and TN from Dr. Alan Gregg, Europe, regarding future in Europe, 1940; 7 pages (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - TLS from F.H., Windrose Farm, Harmon on Hudson to Maurice Hindus, no year September 2; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - ALS from H., Prague, to Maurice Hindus regarding escape, 1939 April 24; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - ALS from H., Prague, to Maurice Hindus regarding escape, 1939 October 16; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - ALS from H., Prague, to Maurice Hindus regarding escape, 1939 November 24; 2 pages (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - ALS-Russian, from Nikolai Harintov regarding personal, 1929 December 21; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - TLS from Frederic J. Haskin, Washington D.C., to Maurice Hindus regarding Mexico, 1938 August 23; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - ALS-German from Helen to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1938 September 10; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - ALS-Czech from Helen, Czechoslovakia to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1938 October 9; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - ALS-German from Helen to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1938 October 14; 2 pages (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - ALS-German from Helen to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1938 October 21; 2 pages (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - ALS-German from Helen to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1938 October 24; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - ALS-German from Helen, Prague, to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1938 November 25; 2 pages (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - ALS-German from Helen, Prague to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1938 December 17; 2 pages (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - ALS from Helen, Prague, to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1939 January 27; 3 pages (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - ALS from Helen, Prague, to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1939 October 9; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - TCS from Helen, Praha, to Maurice Hindus regarding personal, 1969 January 24; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - TLS from United States High Commissioner for Germany, Frankfurt, to Maurice Hindus regarding Mrs. Claasen, 1950 August 14; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 102)
  - TLS-German from Franz Hoellering, Stamford, Connecticut to Taussig, 1938 June 5; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 103)
  - TLS-German from Franz Hoellering, Stamford, Connecticut to Hermann, 1938 June 5; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 104)
  - TLS from Rudolf Hub, Lima, Peru, to Maurice Hindus regarding escape from Czech, 1950 November 30; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 105)
  - TLS from A.L. Hunter, Houston, Texas, to Maurice Hindus regarding criticism, 1941; 2 pages (Box 1, Folder 106)
  - TLS from Henry Hurwitz, New York City, to Maurice Hindus regarding Louis Golding, 1927 December 9; 1 page (Box 1, Folder 107)
  - TLS, Bill Mouell to Hindus, Budapest, regarding personal, 1939 January 31 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - ALS, Karen to Hindus, 19?? March 5 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - TL, Hindus to Justin (his stockbroker), regarding stock, 1956 December 27 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Hindus to Nannine, New York city, regarding personal, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - TL, Hindus to Nannane Joseph, Dallas, Texas, regarding personal, 1939 March 7 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Nannine Joseph to Hindus, New York, New York, regarding personal, 1938 November 17 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Norman A. Imrie to Hindus, Culver, Indiana, regarding Colgate commencement, 1931 June 22 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - TC, To: J.N., Warsaw, regarding letter from fugitives, 1939 December 12 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - TL, A. Johnson to Hindus, London, regarding Darkening Device, 1938 November 7 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - TLS, Louis Johnson to Hindus, Clarksburg, West Virginia, regarding personal, 1941 August 8 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - TC, ALS, Hindus to Louis Johnson, Johnson to Os, Moscow to Washington D.C. to ?, regarding happy new year, 1943 December 30, 1944 January 3 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - TL, Secretary of Defense to Hindus, Washington, D.C., regarding congressional record, 1949 July 1 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - TLS, Louis Johnson to Hindus, Washington, regarding conference of foreigns policy, 1949 December 5 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - TLS, Hindus to Louis (Johnson?), regarding personal, 1950 September 15 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - TLS, Louis Johnson to Hindus, Washington, regarding personal, 1950 September 19 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Louis Johnson to Hindus, Clarksburg, West Virginia, regarding personal, 1952 June 30 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - ALS, Nadine R. Kavinoky to Hindus, Pasadena, California, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - TLS, Bradley Kelly to Hindus, New York, New York, regarding Mark Twain Book Exchange Program, 1962 February 6 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Telegram, Kingsley Martin (New Statesman London) to Hindus, Praha Hotel, Tatranska, Lumnitsa, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - ALS-Russian, O. & F. Klezovich to Mouceii, regarding health problem, 1959 December 28 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - ALS-Russian, O. & F. Klezovich to Mouceii, regarding visit, 1958 April 1 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - ALS-Russian, O. & F. Klezovich to Mouceii, regarding health problem, 1959 February 9 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - ALS, Arlie and Sheldon Kling to Hindus, Utica, New York, regarding personal, 1939 May 3 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - ALS-German, Eruq Laupudorfooa (?) to Hindus, Praha, 1938 December 14 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - TLS, Hindus to Benn W. Levy, New York, New York; TL, Benn W. Levy to Frank Goldschmied; TL, Benn W. Levy to Commander Edgar Young; TLS Benn W. Levy to Hindus, S.W.S., regarding business invitation, 1938 December 29, 1939 January 31, 1939 January 31, 1939 July 10 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - TL, Brackett Lewis to Friends of Masaryk Institute, New York, New York, regarding newsletter, 1939 September 14 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - TLS-Russian, F.V. Lindye & V. Danich to Comrade Surhamyanu, Moscow, regarding Hindus-Journalist Papers, 1928 August 3 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - TLS Robert F. Logan to Hindus, California, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - TLS, Hamilton C. Macdongall to Hindus, Wellesley College, Massachusetts, regarding personal news, 1928 April 21 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - TLS, TC, Lincoln MacVeagh to Hindus, New York City, regarding Kataev Royalties, 1930 August 13 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - TLS, Ken McCormick to Hindus, New York, regarding Will Durant, 1954 January 4 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - TLS, Ken McCormick to Hindus, New York, New York, regarding ad, 1967 March 20 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - ALS, Alice Joyce McDonald to Hindus, Yellowknife, N.W.T., regarding personal, 1950 November 15 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - TLS, Vera A. Micheles to Hindus, New York, New York, regarding Bessarabia, 1929 April 19 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - ALS, Olga Milchakova to Hindus, regarding personal, 1968 October 18 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - ALS, Olga Milchakova to Hindus, Krasnodar, USSR, regarding Christmas, 1969 December 10 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - TLS, A.V. Miller to Hindus, New York, regarding reprint request "Medical Mission"-Czech, 1946 September 30 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - TLS, Jan Munzer to Hindus, New York, regarding Czechoslovakia-Song of Hussites, 1940 November 9 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - TLS, Jan Munzer to Hindus, New York, [1938 or 1939] August 1 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - ALS, Ldenka Munzer to Hindus, New York, regarding help, 1940 November 24 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - ALS, Marion K. Murray to Hindus, Lancaster, Pennsylvania, regarding Lyons & Durandy, 1939 April 9 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - ALS, Louis Neyman to Hindus, Washington, D.C., regarding Christmas, 1969 December 18 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - TLS, E. Khadje Nouri to Hindus, Teheran, regarding personal, 1948 January 26 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - TLS, Branko Novakovic to Hindus, Beograd, regarding Mr. Kardelj, 1961 June 15 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - ALS, Olivia Oglesky=Suider (?) to Hindus, New York, New York (?), undated (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - TL, Hindus to Mr. Ostahov, Metropole Hotel, regarding denied travel in USSR, 1936 July 9 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - ALS-Russian, O.E. Paikovae to Comrade Hindus, Moscow, regarding personal, 1929 October 14 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - PCS, Albert & Louise Parry to Hindus, Phnom-Penh, Cambodia, regarding postcard, 1968 June 8 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - TLS, Albert Parry to Hindus, Colgate University, regarding personal, 1968 September 12 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - TLS, Faroslav Pipek to Hindus, Prague, regarding Law and life in US, 1939 February 14 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - TLS, Russell Potter to Hindus, Columbia University, 1951 May 15 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - TLS-French, The President to the National Czechoslovak Consul to Hindus (?), Praha, 1938 November 15 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - TLS, Ray to Hindus (?), regarding personal, 1968 March 1 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - TLS, Ray to Hindus (?), regarding personal, 1967 August 23 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - ALS, Rebecca to Hindus, 1938? (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - TLS, George F. Rogers to Hindus, Toronto, regarding article error, 1949 July 19 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - TLS, John McCook to Hindus, California, regarding personal, 1967 April 30 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - TLS, Rosamond to Hindus, Chicago, IL, regarding Sylvia von Eltz, 1940 October 18 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - TLS, Galen Starr Ross to Hindus, Detroit, Michigan, regarding meeting, 1939 February 2 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - A. Rotheim to Hindus, New York, New York, regarding info request, 1925 December 2 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - TLS, Oswald Ryan to Hindus, Washington, regarding personal, 1938 November 5 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - ALS, Oswald Ryan to Hindus, Houston, Texas, regarding personal, 1967 March 31 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - TL, Hindus to Oswald Ryan, regarding personal, 1950 July 14 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - TLS, Oswald Ryan to Hindus, Washington, regarding personal, 1950 August 23 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - TL, Hindus to Oswal Ryan, regarding personal (missing pages), 1951 April 27 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - TLS, Robert H. Schaffer to Hindus, New York, New York; TL, Hindus to Robert H. Schaffer, regarding Soviet Publication, 1956 January 26, 1955 December 27 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - TL, Hindus to Vincent Sheean, Dallas, Texas, regarding personal, 1939 March 7 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - TL, R.B. Shipley to Hindus, Department of State, undated (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - TLS, Bill Shirer to Hindus, Switzerland, regarding personal, 1938 October 27 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - TLS, Sol Silverman to Hindus, San Francisco, California, regarding Emanu-el, 1928 January 16 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - TL, Hindus to Jimmie Sheean, New York City; Jimmy Sheean to Hindus, Vermont, regarding letter to Simonov, 1951 May 17, 1951 April 30 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - TL, Bill Shirer to Hindus, Brussells, regarding personal, 1938 November 14 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - TLS, Kveta Simonikova to Hindus, Praha, regarding personal, 1946 January (?), June (?) 25 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - ALS, Tom Skeyhill to Hindus, Florence, regarding travel, 1924 November 24 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - TLS, B.E. Skvirsky to Hindus, Washington, D.C., regarding women and youth in USSR, 1927 December 6 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - TLS, Harrison Smith to Hindus, New York, New York, regarding personal, 1929 August 3 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - 5 TLS, 1 TN, between Jessica Smith and Hindus, New York, regarding famine, 1937 October-November (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - TC, Hindus to Robert Smith, regarding leaving Colgate, 1968 November 26 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Hindus, New York City, Edition of "The Spectator" London, England, 1939 June 28 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - TLS, Russell Speirs to Hindus, Colgate University, regarding visit, 1969 May 20 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - TL, Hindus to Jan Sralinski, Jamestown, Tennessee, regarding interview with Pilsudski, 1928 April 27 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - TLS, Vilhjalmur Stefanson to Albert Parry, Dartmouth College, 1956 March 21 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - TL, Hindus to Mrs. Stone, regarding Volge Germans, 1968 March 6 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - TLS, Fran Sweeney to Hindus, Brookline, Massachusetts, regarding personal, 1939 February 20 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - TLS, Sylvia to Hindus, Djursholm, regarding personal, 1939 April 24 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - TLS, Jedediah Tringle to Hindus, Brooklyn, New York, regarding "Bibulous and their Rebel Sons", 1928 February 15 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - TLS, L.M. Tolokonski to Hindus, regarding leaving, 1935 May 31 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - TLS-Russian, Vera (Beyna) to Hindus, regarding personal, 1966 March 15 (Box 2, Folder 88)